Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/alexandra-alex-g-357004a6 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
Land Use Planning
Zoning
Research

Certifications
AICP Certified

Alexandra (Alex) G.

President and CEO, Desire Line Greater New Orleans Region

Summary

Alex is a certified Planner with over 13 years of experience and founder of Desire Line, an urban and regional planning, grants management, recovery and strategic implementation company. Alex has a history of excellence in managing complex, challenging projects that require enhanced logistics, strategic long-range planning, and focused efforts across multiple teams with programmed workflows and short, high-pressure deadlines. Her collaborative attitude and unprecedented work ethic has built strong, lasting relationships within and across local, regional, state and federal agencies.

Alex specializes in project and grant program development, administration and management, team building, urban and regional planning, policy and local code research and development, outreach and communication, ArcGIS, and mapping. She has extensive experience developing and managing projects, policies, and programs focused on natural functions, watershed management, and flood risk mitigation; supporting climate adaption and long-term resilience strategies; administering and supporting local planning, permitting, code enforcement, transportation, and floodplain management offices and services; and performing land use, multimodal, and comprehensive planning studies and master plans.

As Resilience Planning Manager with Louisiana's Office of Community Development, she worked alongside state and local stakeholders to implement the Louisiana Watershed Initiative, leading a long-range vision for the state to mitigate future flood risk based on natural boundaries. She is also the former Planning, Zoning, and Code Enforcement Director of St. John the Baptist Parish, LA. In this role, she and her team successfully worked with the public and elected officials to draft, adopt, and implement a content neutral sign code, adult and live entertainment standards, comprehensive nonconforming use/structure/site standards, a hearing procedure to administratively adjudicate code violations,

and a variety of nuisance standards. Alex also served as the APA LA Metro New Orleans Section Director and worked as a Planner in Jefferson Parish, LA, assisting with the establishment and promotion of pedestrian and businesses improvement districts. She graduated with honors from UNO (Masters, 2011) and Loyola University New Orleans (BFA, 2009).

Experience

Desire Line LLC
President and CEO
September 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)
New Orleans, Louisiana, United States

Established 100% woman-owned company to provide improved management and performance of professional services including, but not limited to:

- # Disaster recovery support
- # Project management and project scoping support
- # Master planning, including community, street, site, pedestrian and stormwater management
- # Local code drafting, with a focus on advancing community assets and longterm resilience
- # Federal and state grants administration including scoping, application and implementation
- # Local operations maintenance and support
- # Project, community, regional and statewide outreach and engagement support

Louisiana Watershed Initiative
Resilience Planning Manager
October 2018 - September 2021 (3 years)
New Orleans, Louisiana, United States

As a Resilience Planning Manager with Louisiana's Office of Community Development-Disaster Recovery Unit (OCD-DR), Alex worked alongside state and local stakeholders to implement the Louisiana Watershed Initiative, which was launched in August 2018 by Governor John Bel Edwards and aims to lead a long-range vision for the state's multi-pronged approach to mitigating future flood risk focused on natural boundaries. Visit watershed.la.gov to learn more.

Director of Planning and Zoning
January 2016 - September 2018 (2 years 9 months)

Alex devoted much of her time improving government operations in St. John the Baptist Parish, where she was the Planning, Zoning, and Code Enforcement Director. Known for a positive and professional enthusiasm; she and her team successfully worked with the public and elected officials to draft, adopt and implement a content neutral sign code, adult and live entertainment standards, comprehensive nonconforming use standards, a hearing procedure to adjudicate code violations and a variety of nuisance standards (i.e. high grass, trash/debris, junk vehicles), while increasing program efficiency and the quality of customer service within the Department.

She also conducted private property damage assessments as Emergency Operations Center (EOC) staff, oversaw efforts and reporting requirements for the NFIP's Community Rating System (CRS) program, and performed damages assessments, including the inventory of over 1,000 properties, management of over 15 team members, coordination of data collection and reporting, and issuance of substantial damage declaration letters in compliance with NFIP requirements. Her efforts garnered the attention of GOHSEP regional staff, where (upon request) she performed a training for Region 6 EOC staff on how to effectively perform and report damage assessments for private property in the wake of a disaster with limited resources.

APA LA Metro New Orleans Section

Director

January 2017 - January 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Alex served as the APA LA Metro New Orleans Section Director, where she has increased networking and educational opportunities, volunteer events, and membership outreach and participation, which has contributed to a 28% increase in membership since the start of her term in January 2017.

Saint John the Baptist Parish Zoning and Regulatory Administrator April 2015 - January 2016 (10 months)

LaPlace, Louisiana

As Zoning Regulatory Administrator, Alex worked directly with contractors, owners, architects, engineers, and the public to process land use, zoning, subdivision, and variance requests, as well as site plan and building permit applications. She supervised permit clerks, coordinators, and planning

and zoning inspectors within the Planning and Zoning Department. She was also responsible for administrative approvals and presenting land use recommendations to the Planning Commission, Zoning Board of Adjustment and Parish Council.

Jefferson Parish Planning Department Planner II July 2009 - March 2015 (5 years 9 months) Jefferson, LA

- Jefferson Parish Planning Employee of the Year, 2012.
- Strategic planning liaison to Fat City Friends Inc., 2012-2014. Coordinated planning activities, assisted in grant applications, and supported revitalization efforts
- Collaborated, as a member of the Fat City Mural Selection Committee, with the New Orleans Arts Council to create an 'outdoor art gallery' in Fat City, 2014 to present.
- Strategic planning liaison to the Fat City Advisory Board, 2011 to 2012 (precursor of Fat City Friends, Inc.). Coordinated planning activities; developed and implemented two-year work program; administered board meetings; formulated and implemented a capital improvement review procedure and plan of projects; analyzed project and neighborhood development, crime and tax data; researched and advised on implementation strategies for a Fat City BDD; produced a two-day Fat City redevelopment workshop; revitalized original '1970s Fat City logo,' initiated Fat City rebranding campaign, and developed and presented the Board's final report.
- Composed technical text and map studies, as well as briefs, presentations, grant applications, and maps
- Edited and maintained parish GIS mapping system and and other record keeping systems
- Presented and discussed project scope and draft recommendations to public and private organizations, interested stakeholders, and boards and agencies
- Fielded public inquiries related to zoning code interpretations, proposed study recommendations, and assigned cases

Meyer Consulting Engineers Corporation Executive Assistant July 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 2 months) Metairie, Louisiana Managed and maintained accounting processes including, but not limited to, accounts receivable, accounts payable, reconciliations, general ledgers, and monthly budgets

Metairie Park Country Day School Buyer Administrator May 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 4 months) Metairie, Louisiana

Purchased, maintained, and budgeted for artistic supplies for over 40 staff members and 400 students in the school's summer art program

Education

University of New Orleans

Master of Urban and Regional Planning, Housing, Community and Economic

Development · (2009 - 2011)

Loyola University New Orleans
Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA), Painting and Sculpture · (2006 - 2009)